Ravi Sindri

South Jordan, Utah, United States



sindirirk@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ravisindri

Summary

Testing practice technology leader with over 20 years of IT industry experience. Managed large projects with TCV 2MN+ with a total portfolio varying from 10MN - 12MN. Responsible for global delivery management, establishing TCoE, test process governance, complex test strategy definition for large programs, solution designing/development, proof-of-concept (PoC's), RFI/RFP responses, pre-sales/business development, publish case studies & ROI, forecasting & budget planning, client relationship management, business review meetings, bottom line improvement, resource utilization, onsite/offshore ratio optimization, people management, performance appraisals & normalization, staffing & resource fulfilment, competency building, attrition management etc. Manage globally distributed delivery teams for various ISVs and enterprises. Traveled extensively onsite, visiting customers to formulate delivery teams and implementation of program roadmap.

Experience

Cignití AVP - Global Delivery

Cigniti Technologies

Dec 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months +)

cignití Director - Global Delivery

Cigniti Technologies

Oct 2014 - Nov 2019 (5 years 2 months)

Being part of the leadership team, I am responsible for managing teams globally, setting up TCoE, competence building, presales, solution design & implementation, account management, project management, conducting webinars, organization initiatives etc.

Cignití Sr. Manager - Global Delivery

Cigniti Technologies

Nov 2012 - Sep 2014 (1 year 11 months)

Managed projects to ensure quality deliverable. Led test automation efforts and work closely with Enterprise Solutions Group in designing enterprise level Test Automation Solutions and present the same to prospects to show the technology and business benefits.

Manager - Technical Services

AppLabs

Oct 2011 - Nov 2012 (1 year 2 months)

Managed test automation teams, defined test automation frameworks, worked closely with Solution Engineering Group in providing valuable inputs for various automation proposals.

Associate Manager - Technical Services

AppLabs

Apr 2010 - Sep 2011 (1 year 6 months)

Designed, Developed and Implemented Test Automation Framework for large enterprise level multi tier system implementation. Automated ATG, SAP, WebServices etc. to establish end to end testing. Travelled to the UK to implement the same for a large retail client.

AppLabs Project Lead

AppLabs

Jun 2007 - Mar 2010 (2 years 10 months)

Designed, developed and implemented test automation solutions for projects that have complex GUI and functionality such as Semiconductor domain.

Lead Test Automation Engineer

Impetus

Jun 2004 - Jun 2007 (3 years 1 month)

Developed & Implemented Test Automation Framework using QTP, and automated 500+ test scenarios. Travelled to the US to train client teams on the automation suite.

Senior Software Engineer

MGRM Net Ltd.

Jul 2002 - Jun 2004 (2 years)

Developed and unit tested ERP applications

Senior Software Engineer

Zensoft Solutions Ltd.

Jul 2000 - Jun 2002 (2 years)

Developed banking solutions

Education

Khalikote College, Berhampur, Orissa

B.Com, Commerce

1990 - 1995

City High School, Berhampur, Orissa

10th, Maths

1989 - 1990

Skills

Test Automation Architect • Test Automation • Automation • Quality Center • Project Management • SDLC • Software Project Management • Manual Testing • Testing • Test Management